靈
書
妙
探
靈
書
妙
探
第四季 第十六集
本字幕由 YYeTs人人影視 原創翻譯制作
僅供學習 禁止用于任何商業盈利行為
更多影視更新 請登陸 www.YYeTs.com
■
翻譯：DJ  覺欞  慢慢  sakura  一不二  midichlorian  sel耀靚  小蠻腰
時間軸：子衿 Remember 玖月
■
校對：草草  大衛熊     后期&監制：瓜瓜
《靈書妙探》前情提要
Previously on "Castle"...
舉起手來  托馬斯·蓋奇  你被鋪了
Hands in the air. Thomas Gage, you're under arrest.
你們掌握的有關我的證據都會消失無蹤
Everything that you have on me, it's all going away.
我也很想知道他是怎么從你們眼皮子底下
I'm very interested in knowing how he got out of
從牢房溜出去的
that holding cell on your watch.
卡塞爾
Castle...
里克·卡塞爾也有詞窮的時候
Rick Castle at a loss for words.
索菲亞·特納
Sophia Turner.
你好  里克
Hello, Rick.
你是德瑞克·斯道姆系列小說里的
You're Clara Strike from
克萊拉·斯瑞克
the Derrick Storm books?
歡迎來到中情局
Welcome to the CIA.
蓋奇曾是我們的王牌特工
Gage was our most effective asset.
他變節了
He went rogue.
潘朵拉是蓋奇任務的代號
Pandora is the code name for gage's mission.
他是誰
Who is he?
尼爾森·布萊克利博士
Dr. Nelson Blakely.
他來了
There he is.
他曾是中情局的傳奇
He was a legend at the agency.
他的方法是找到能引起
His approach was to find a small event
大沖突的小事件
that could trigger a large event.
布萊克利是策劃潘朵拉的人
Blakely is the one who planned pandora.
那將遠超出最壞的設想
This is beyond a worst-case scenario.
布萊克利博士  到底是怎么回事
Dr. Blakely, what's going on?
我發現了一個關鍵環節
I found a linchpin
將會給我們的國家帶來毀滅
that will bring about the end of our country as we know it.
-布萊克利博士  -他們來了
- Dr. Blakely - they're here.
等等  等一下
Wait! Wait!
-貝克特  -卡塞爾
- Beckett! - Castle!
這邊門打不開了
This door won't open.
我這邊也是
Yeah, mine won't either.
門框被撞變形了
I think the crash bent the frame.
我們得找點東西把玻璃打碎
We need something to break the glass.
我的槍
My gun.
卡塞爾  我
Castle, I can't...
我找不到
I can't find it.
可能是我們撞車的時候被撞飛了
I-I think it got knocked out when we got hit.
幫我找找
Help me look for it.
我被卡住了
I'm stuck.
什么叫你被卡住了
What do you mean, you're stuck?
我的安全帶打不開了
I mean, my belt is jammed.
座位也動不了
And the seat won't move.
刀子呢  你有刀嗎
Okay, what about a knife? Do you have a knife?
有
Yeah.
在后車廂里
In the trunk.
聽著  我們沒時間了
Okay, look, we're running out of time.
你得看看能不能找到槍
I need you to see if you can find that gun,
然后我們把安全打斷
and we'll just shoot the belt off.
我摸不到
I can't feel it.
-卡塞爾  -等等  等等
- Castle. - Okay, hang on. Hang on.
待著別動
Okay. Just stay here.
我找到了
I found it.
卡塞爾
Castle?
Castle!
我想有女兒在犯罪現場的好處
I guess the good thing about having your daughter at crime scenes is,
就是她能給你帶干衣服
she can bring you dry clothes.
謝了
Thanks.
還有
And, um...
謝謝
Thanks.
你也會為我這么做的
You'd have done the same for me.
是啊
Yeah.
可能吧
Probably.
我只是很高興你找到了我的槍
I'm just glad you found my gun.
車掉水里這事
that whole, uh, sinking car thing--
看電影比親身體驗爽多了
much cooler in movies than it is in real life.
我也想說  我還是更喜歡間諜片而不是參與其中
And for the record, I prefer watching spy thrillers to being in them.
好吧
So...
老實交代
Tell me...
為什么你們的受害人長得那么像
How can your victim look like Nelson Blakely
本應死了十年的尼爾森·布萊克利
when he supposedly died ten years ago?
是啊  我
Yeah, I...
是啊  很奇怪不是嗎
Yeah, weird, isn't it?
是  奇了怪了
Yeah. Weird.
假死  汽車落水
Fake deaths, car in the water--
你們就不覺得現在
Don't you think now is a good time
應該告訴我們到底怎么回事嗎
to tell us what the hell is going on?
不好意思  哈維爾
Uh... I'm sorry, Javi.
機密行動
It's classified.
我在特種部隊待過
I was special forces.
機密行動以前是我的家常便飯
I used to eat classified for breakfast.
這個作家小子為什么就能知道
And yet writer boy can know?
好吧  我去那邊跟海港巡邏隊一起
Okay. I'll be over there with harbor patrol
看怎么把你的車從水里撈出來
trying to figure out how to get your unit out of the drink.
很高興你們沒事
I'm glad you're okay.
謝謝
Thank you.
作家小子
Writer boy?
-你覺得兇手是蓋奇  -對
- So you think our shooter was Gage? - Yeah.
我覺得他在除掉每一個
I think he's getting rid of anyone
會暴露他變節行動的人
that could expose his rogue operations.
他干的真是不錯啊
Well, he's doing a pretty good job.
我們到現在都不知道潘朵拉是什么
We still have no idea what Pandora is.
我們知道布萊克利害怕了
Well, we know that Blakely was afraid.
我們也知道他在進行一些
And we know that he was working on something
足以威脅國家未來的研究
that was big enough to threaten the future of this country.
我們只是不知道他在研究什么
We just don't know what the hell he was working on.
他的生活中一定有些線索
There's gotta be a clue somewhere in his life.
或許他尸體能泄露點玄機
Maybe there's something on the body that will tell us.
不  我們檢查過了  他兜里什么都沒有
No. We checked. There was nothing in his pockets.
不過從衣兜被翻出來的樣子可以猜測
But the way they were turned out makes me think
有人翻找過并把里面的東西拿走了
someone went through and emptied them.
蓋奇
Gage.
萊恩  找人搜查一下建筑物
Ryan, get some teams to search the building.
-我們要找什么  -我也不知道
- What are we looking for? - I don't know.
但是他帶我們過來總是有原因的
But he brought us here for a reason.
蕾妮  你能不能從他身上發現點什么
Lanie, see what you can find on him--
牙齒  傷疤  指紋  紋身
Dental, scars, prints, tattoos,
任何能告訴我們
anything that might tell us--
-他死了  -是啊
- He's dead. - Yeah.
聽著  我能解釋
Look, I can explain.
上車
Get in the car.
你們在做什么
What the hell did you think you were doing?
你想讓我們做的  找布萊克利
What you wanted, finding blakely.
你破解了他的密碼就不想著來告訴我一聲嗎
You cracked his code and you didn't even think to notify me?
我得為卡塞爾說句話
Look, in Castle's defense,
這事希望渺茫
it was a long shot,
他不想自己判斷錯誤而浪費了你的時間
and he didn't want to waste your time if he was wrong.
何況當時我們正要帶他過來
And we were bringing the guy in...
卻被人殺了  還是在你的監護下
When he was killed, in your custody.
你們在碼頭做什么
What were you doing at the docks?
-他讓我們帶他去的  -為什么
- He asked us to take him there. - Why?
我們不知道
We don't know.
你們問出任何事來了嗎
Well, did you learn anything?
問出來了
Yes.
他受雇分析美國的弱點
He was hired to analyze the United States for vulnerabilities.
他說他發現了經濟方面的一個漏洞
He said he found a weakness in our economy--
一個令人意想不到的關鍵
an unexpected linchpin--that,
如果有人攻擊此處  多米諾骨牌就會接連倒下
if someone went after it, would start the dominos falling.
會引發什么后果
Falling toward what?
國家會整個崩潰
The end of our country as we know it.
那我們下一步做什么
So what's our next move?
沒有下一步了
There is no next move.
至少你們倆沒有
Not for you two.
讓你們參與此事就是個錯誤
It was a mistake bringing you into the loop.
我本來以為
You know, I really thought--
我以為你有改變
I really thought you had changed.
結果呢
But you know what?
你還跟以前一樣
You are the same reckless,
是個魯莽  幼稚  自我為中心的混蛋
immature, self-centered jackass that you always were,
你將整個調查置于危險之中
and you've put this investigation at risk.
-對不起  -對不起
Look, I'm sorry-- you're sorry?
我們面臨的是下一個911  或許更糟
We are on the verge of the next 9/11 or worse.
這不是你寫的書  里克
This isn't one of your damn books, Rick.
這是真實生活  如果出了問題
This is real life, and when things go bad,
你不能像對我們的事那樣改寫個結局了事
you can't just rewrite the ending like you did with us.
把他們帶出去
Get them both out of here.
這么說  你跟她睡過了
So...You slept with her.
是是  我跟她睡了
Yeah, yeah. Yeah, I slept with her.
還有別人嗎
Have there been others?
-女人嗎  -你的繆斯
- Women? - Muses.
沒了  怎么
No. Why?
我就想看看繆斯俱樂部到底有多少人
I just wanted to see how big the club was. That's all.
同志們  有進展嗎
Hey, guys. What do you got?
首先  根本就沒有這么個俱樂部
First off, there is no club.
其次  我們不跟這個案子了  記得嗎
And second, we're off the case if you recall.
是不跟他們查了  我自己還有個兇殺案
We're off their case. I still have a murder to solve.
可你的主要嫌疑犯恰好
Where your chief suspect
是中情局行動中牽涉到的人
is smack-dab in the middle of a CIA operation.
我才不管他牽涉到哪里
I don't care what he's in the middle of.
托馬斯·蓋奇殺了三個人
Thomas Gage killed three people.
其中一人當時還是由我監護
One of them was in my custody.
他把我們關在車后備箱里
He locked us in a trunk
他還把我的警車撞進了哈德孫河里
and then he sent my cruiser to the bottom of the hudson.
蓋奇是個訓練有素的秘密特工
Gage is a trained covert operative.
你不可能抓到他的
There's no way you can catch him.
我可以  只要想出來他下面會去哪
Yes, I can, if I figure out where he was going.
我們查明布萊克利在研究什么
We find out what Blakely was working on,
從而找到那個關鍵點
we find the linchpin.
找到關鍵點  就能找到蓋奇
We find the linchpin, we find Gage.
在倉庫找到什么了嗎
Anything on the warehouse?
有啊  你們倆走了之后  聯調局的人來了
Yeah, right after you guys left, the feds showed up
中止了我們的調查
and shut us down.
不過我們查到了死者尼爾森·布萊克利的一些信息
But we did find something on your vic Nelson Blakely.
他的指紋和長島的斯科特·麥克格雷格相吻合
His prints came back as a Scott McGregor from long island city.
問題是  這個麥克格雷格貌似只存在于文件上
Problem is, McGregor seems to only exist on paper.
我們在現實世界里查不到他的蹤跡
We can't find any trace of him in the real world.
你們派人去列出的地址盤查了嗎
Did you guys send units to the listed address?
去了  住在那的人說從沒聽說過他
Yeah, and the family living there had never heard of him,
也沒人認得他的照片
and no one recognized his photo.
肯定有人認識他
Well, someone must have known him.
是有人認識
Someone did.
他玩象棋  象棋沒法一個人玩
He plays chess. That's not a solo sport.
你不是不跟這案子了嗎
I thought you were off the case.
你聽到索菲亞怎么說我的了
Well, you heard what Sophia said.
一個魯莽  幼稚  自我為中心的混蛋
I'm a reckless, immature, self-centered jackass.
如果你固執到一定要繼續查的地步
If you're stubborn enough to keep going,
那我就笨到跟著你繼續的地步
I'm stupid enough to go with you.
好吧  你們去排查一下城里所有的象棋公園
All right. You guys canvass all of the chess parks in the city.
看看能不能找到跟他對過弈的人
Let's see if we can dig up some of his opponents.
貝克特
Beckett.
什么
What?
什么叫"尸體就沒來"
What do you mean, the body never arrived?
他們中途把尸體攔截了
They intercepted it at transport.
他們申請到了法院指令
Apparently, they had a court order.
不可能
That's impossible.
怎么可能這么快就申請到法院指令
How could they get a court order that fast?
我怎么知道  要不你去問問你女朋友
I don't know. Maybe you should ask your girlfriend.
女朋友
Girlfriend?
行了吧  我們確實一起睡了
Yes, okay. We slept together.
但那是很久以前了  有什么大不了的
It was a long time ago. What's the big deal?
沒什么  愛跟誰睡跟誰睡
There is no big deal. Sleep with whoever you want.
多多益善
The more the merrier.
我把毒物檢測報告拿來了
I have those, uh, toxicology reports you wanted.
好  放那兒吧  親愛的
Oh, yes. Just set 'em there, sweetie.
謝謝
Thank you.
你喜歡你的新實習吧
So enjoying your new internship?
我知道了很多新東西
Well, I'm learning a lot.
知道太多了
Too much I think.
我還以為最惡心的部分會是死尸呢
And I thought the dead bodies were going to be the grossest part.
有意思  晚安
Funny. Good night.
那么貝克特說的是誰
So who was Beckett talking about?
跟你無關  快去睡覺
None of your business. Now go to bed.
在碼頭出現的那個女的是誰
The woman at the docks, who is she?
不是誰
Nobody.
快去睡覺
Now go to bed.
我看到你看她的眼神了
I saw the way you looked at her.
她絕不是一般人
She's not nobody.
她是誰都無所謂
Well, it doesn't matter who she is
反正我們不會再見面了
because I am never going to see her again.
現在快去睡覺吧
Now go to bed.
要知道  你要是這么對我遮遮掩掩的
You know, if you're going to keep secrets from me,
我或許也會開始對你有所隱瞞
I might start keeping secrets from you, too.
你這年紀  瞞著爸爸點事也挺好的
At your age, I'm thinking, that might be a good idea.
索菲亞
Sophia.
晚上好  里克
Hello, Rick.
你怎么  做什么  你怎么進來的
How--what are you--how did-- how did you get in here?
我是中情局特工
I'm CIA.
你的小說現在還改編成漫畫了
So they're turning them into graphic novels now?
是的
Yeah. Um...
第一本反響不錯  他們還要改編一部
The first one did well, so they're gonna do another.
你覺得怎么樣  她看上去像我嗎
So what do you think, she look like me?
你到底來做什么
Uh... What are you doing here?
你們還在追查蓋奇不是嗎
You're going after Gage, aren't you?
沒有  我們不能跟這個案子了  記得嗎
No. We're off the case, remember?
還是過去的你更善于說謊
Mm. You used to be a better liar.
我知道你們在查布萊克利的化名
I know you've been looking into Blakely's aliases.
沒關系  里克  我不介意
It's okay, Rick. I don't mind.
事實上  我希望你繼續追查這個案子
In fact, I want you on this case.
-但  -我知道我說過什么
- But... -I know what I said,
但我也知道事關重大
but I also know what's at stake.
之前讓你和貝克特加入調查
Bringing you and Beckett on board
并不是一個很受歡迎的決定
was not a popular decision,
而且由于布萊克利的死  我得表明立場
And after what happened with Blakely, I had to make a stand.
但是我知道你的能力
But I know what kind of asset you can be.
我知道不管我說什么你都會繼續追查下去
I know you'll just keep digging no matter what I say.
這是你的天性
It's your nature.
你總得知道故事會有怎樣的結局
You need to know how the story ends.
就像她身上的故事一樣
Like with her.
她知道這些嗎
Does she know about this?
那是...
Well, that's...
你總是喜歡玩危險游戲
You always did like playing with dynamite.
只是小心別玩火自焚
Just be careful it doesn't blow up in your face.
她與眾不同
She's different.
是嗎
Is she?
還是只是你一廂情愿
Or do you just think she is?
聽說你們和我們一樣查布萊克利進了死胡同
I heard you hit the same dead end with Blakely as we did.
我想你們或許可以試一下這條線索
I thought you might be able to try this.
這就是布萊克利去碼頭要找的東西
It's what Blakely was looking for at the pier.
我們是在一個放著機票  現金和假身份證的
We found it in a go bag with plane tickets, cash,
沖鋒包里找到的
and some fake I.D.S.
銀行賬號
Account numbers?
全都是國內銀行的
All from domestic banks.
鑒于布萊克利是美國公民
And since Blakely was a U.S. Citizen--
你們沒有權力繼續調查他
You're prohibited from looking into them.
但是你們有
But you guys aren't.
這些帳號可能指向他的雇主的身份
And those accounts may contain clues as to who hired him.
我想你仍然好奇故事的結局吧
And assuming you still want to know how the story ends...
只是這一次務必及時向我通報消息
Just keep me in the loop this time.
還有  里克
And, Rick...
盡量保住自己的性命
Try not to get killed.
我還是挺喜歡你的
I'm still quite fond of you.
小伙子們都去哪兒了
Where are the boys?
他們在象棋公園做排查
They're canvassing chess parks,
看看有沒有人認識布萊克利
looking for anyone that knew Blakely.
你為什么沒有跟他們一起去
And why aren't you with them?
因為我的車正躺在哈德遜河河底
Because my car is at the bottom of the Hudson,
而且除非我上交事故報告
and Gates won't issue me another one
蓋茨就不肯給我配輛新車
until I write up an incident report,
可是這案子是機密所以我又不能寫報告
which I can't do because this case is classified.
你笑什么
What?
沒什么
Nothing.
只是  真是一個關鍵理論的絕佳例證
It's just, that's a perfect example of a linchpin.
這個案子可能永遠不能偵破就因為
This case might go unsolved all because
你拿不到一輛車
you don't have access to a car.
不要逼我開槍打你
Don't make me shoot you.
如果你真開槍打我
Well, if you shoot me,
誰來幫你追查這條線索
who's gonna help you follow this lead?
布萊克利的銀行賬戶信息
Blakely's bank account information.
這就是他去碼頭要找的東西
It's what he was going for on the pier.
如果我們能追蹤他的資產
If we can track his money--
你從哪里得到這個的
Where did you get that?
索菲亞
Sophia.
她昨晚去了我家
She came to my place last night.
-不是你想得那樣  -當然不是
- Not like that. - No, of course.
她不是說你"魯莽  幼稚
So then what happened to "Reckless, immature,
自我為中心"嗎
Self-centered jackass"?
她只是在同事面前表一下姿態
She was posturing for her colleagues.
貝克特  這是一條線索
Beckett, it's a lead.
她希望我們繼續追查此案
She wants us on the case.
你覺得到底發生了什么事
What do you think this is about, huh?
感覺像是情報部門的活動
It smells like an intelligence op.
中情局  國安局還是國土安全部
CIA, NSA, DHS?
就那幾個字母排列組合
Same letters, different alphabet.
我以前部隊里有些兄弟自愿參加情報部門行動
I had some buddies from the service volunteer for intelligence ops.
他們喜歡這份工作嗎
Yeah, how'd they like it?
他們都犧牲了
They all died.
你們認識這個人嗎
Hey, guys. Do you recognize this man?
我還真認識他
Matter of fact, I do.
他大概每周會來這公園兩三次
Uh, he comes to the park two or three times a week.
找人一起下棋
Looks for games.
你還知道些什么
What do you know about him?
他是一個瘋狂的棋手
He's a crazy chess player.
經常棋出怪招
Makes some weird moves,
比如犧牲皇后
like sacrificing his queen
只想看看會發生什么
just to see what happens.
但是他總是會贏
He always wins, though.
你知道他的名字嗎
Do you know his name?
叫斯科特什么的
Scott or something like that.
但是如果你們想多了解一下這個人
But I-if you want to know about this guy,
你們應該去找雅尼聊聊
you should talk to Jani.
雅尼是誰
Jani? Who's Jani?
另一個棋手
Another player.
他跟你們要找的這個人
Him and your guy...
最近經常聚在一起
been spending a lot of time together lately.
布萊克利的六個賬戶總計有兩百萬
So Blakely had over $2 million in six accounts,
但都是用假名開戶
and none of them under his real name.
往里面存款的都是非營利性組織  援助協會
Deposits were made by nonprofits, aid groups,
還有環保組織
environmental organizations.
如果這些真是他的秘密咨詢業務賬戶
So if those were his secret consulting accounts,
那么這些交易中極可能有一筆
it's possible that one of those payments
是用來支付潘多拉計劃的
was for operation Pandora.
沒錯  這兩筆
Exactly. These two.
每筆存入五十萬
Deposits of half a million dollars each.
這一筆是三個月前
This one was from three months ago,
這一筆是一個星期前
and this one was from a week ago.
是他開始和結束的報酬
His start and finish payments.
對  均來自海外賬戶
Mm-hmm. Both from offshore accounts.
但現在賬戶已關閉  是條死胡同
But they're closed. It's a dead end.
我們可能找到條有關布萊克利的線索
We may have a lead on Blakely.
公園里的人說他最近總和這人在一起
Guy in the park said he's been spending time with this man--
雅那切克·斯佰威
Janacek Spivey.
兩屆全國國際象棋冠軍  現在擔任
2-time national chess champion, now an economics professor
國際事務學校的經濟學教授
at the school of international affairs.
一個經濟學教授
An economics professor?
你覺得與這事有關
You think it's related?
我不知道這資料是否有用
Well, I don't know if this helps,
但他還是國際貨幣基金組織
but the guy is also an advisor to the I.M.F.,
聯合國經濟委員會以及
the U.N. Economics Council,
國會財政委員會的顧問
and the congressional finance committee.
對  就是他
Yeah, that's him.
但他說自己叫麥克格雷格  不是布萊克利
But he said his name was McGregor, not Blakely.
你對他了解多少
What do you know about him?
他是個非常厲害的棋手
Um, he was a hell of a chess player.
在我落子之前  他似乎總能洞察
Uh, it seemed like he knew every move I was gonna make
我要走的每一步
before I made it.
不  我是說...
No, I mean...
關于他個人
Personally.
其實他從沒聊過他個人的事
He never really talked about his personal life.
有目擊者稱你們常聊天  談了什么
Witnesses said you spent a lot of time talking. What about?
經濟學理論
Economic theory.
在知道我的職業之后
When he found out what I did,
他就問了我一大堆問題
he had a million questions.
什么樣的問題
What kind of questions?
有關世界的經濟力量
About world economic forces,
歷史上的社會經濟模型
historic socioeconomic models.
有時覺得他比我知道得還多
There were times it seemed like he knew more than I did.
他是個熱忱的發燒友
He was quite the hobbyist.
他可不只是個發燒友
Oh, he was more than just a hobbyist.
他有特別關注過什么東西嗎
Did he focus on anything in specific?
我沒什么印象
Uh, not that I remember.
但他對美國經濟非常關心
Though he was very concerned with the U.S.economy.
他從沒提過家人或朋友嗎
And he never mentioned any family or friends?
-沒有  -他去哪里買東西
- No. - Anywhere he might have shopped?
有任何能看出他住哪的線索嗎
Anything that might indicate where he lived?
沒有  但我覺得他住在聯合廣場
No. B- but I think he lived in Union Square.
為什么這么說
And what makes you say that?
有次我們散步結束
After one of our walks,
我發現把棋盤忘在公園了
uh, I discovered I'd left my chess set in the park.
往回走時  我看見他走向那里的一棟樓
And on my way back, I saw him head into a building there.
你能替我們指出是哪幢樓嗎
Do you think you can identify that building for us?
我想可以
I think so.
我得借下你的車
I gotta borrow your car.
對  他就住這里
Uh, yeah, this is his place right here.
但他叫芬利  不是布萊克利或是麥克格雷格
But he said his name was Finley, not Blakely or McGregor.
謝了
Thanks.
我們要找什么
What are we looking for?
報紙  電腦  電話記錄  賬單
Papers, computers, phone records, bills--
任何能幫我們想明白他在做什么的線索
anything that'll help us figure out what he was up to.
貝克特
Beckett.
我覺得我找到了
Think I found it.
搞什么啊
What the hell?
稅務騷亂
"Tax riots."
歐洲經濟衰竭
"European economic collapse."
伊朗侵略伊拉克
"Iran invades Iraq!"
敘利亞攻擊以色列
"Syria moves on Israel."
美國遣軍駐臺灣
"U.S. commits troops to Taiwan."
美國遣軍駐中東
"U.S. commits troops to Middle East."
俄羅斯攻擊東歐
"Russia moves on Eastern Europe."
這個關鍵要制造出怎樣的后果啊
What kind of an outcome was this linchpin supposed to create?
終結我們所熟知的國家
The end of our country as we know it.
2017年8月  美國投降
預計2700萬傷亡
第三次世界大戰
A third world war.
不可能是真的
This can't be real.
沒人能預言這些
No one can predict all of this.
或許不會
Maybe not,
但有些比我們聰明的人相信他能做的
but a bunch of people smarter than us think he can
也會為了掩蓋這一切而殺人
and would kill to cover it up.
我發現了一個非常脆弱的環節
I found an alarming vulnerability...
看這邊
Over here.
這個環節將帶來
A linchpin that was tied to the economy
稅務騷亂
我們前所未見的
that would cause crisis and devastation
潘多拉
經濟危機和毀滅
beyond anything we'd ever seen.
關鍵
多米諾骨牌會永不停歇的倒下去
The dominos would just never stop falling.
她是誰
Who is she?
我不知道  但就是她了
I don't know, but this is it.
她就是那個關鍵
She's the linchpin.
是第一塊倒下的多米諾  將引發戰爭
The first domino to fall that... leads to war.
我把會給美國
I gave them the blueprint
帶來毀滅的藍圖交給了他們
that will bring out the end of our country as we know it.
"關鍵"殺手
已出現
我得給他們打電話  他們得知道這個
I have to call them. They have to know.
掛掉電話
Put the phone down.
-蓋奇  -快掛電話
- Gage? - Put the phone down now.
快跑
Now run.
-什么  -跑
- What? - Run!
我以為你是壞人
I thought you were the bad guy.
如果我是壞人  你們現在早死了
If I were the bad guy, you'd be dead by now.
這邊走
This way.
不  我的車就在外面
No, my car is out front.
他們盯著你的車  你出去就必死無疑
They're watching your car. You go that way, and you'll die.
外面的人是誰
Who's out there? Who are they?
知道答案和活著出去二選一
You can have answers or you can live.
你來選吧
Your choice.
趴下
Stay down!
我們得聯系中情局的聯絡人
We need to call our CIA contact.
我們得告訴他們發生了什么
We need to tell them what's going on.
不許打電話
No calls.
我們在哪里
Where are we?
安全的地方  但我們沒多少時間了
Someplace safe, but we don't have much time, all right?
我潛逃之前也聽到了風聲
I've been on the grid, I've heard the chatter.
不管到底是什么事  都將于明天發生
Whatever this is, it's going down tomorrow.
你們比我先到布萊克利家  目標是誰
Now you got to Blakely's before me. Who's the target?
你為什么殺了布萊克利和麥格拉
Why did you kill Blakely and McGrath?
我沒殺他們
I didn't.
你還想我再把槍從你手上奪走一次嗎
Come on. You really want me to take that gun away from you again?
-我們沒時間了  -擠點時間
- We don't have the time. - Make time.
做為一個特工
Look, as an asset,
你必須訓練出一些生存技能
you have to develop certain survival skills, all right?
最首要的能力
Chief of which is the ability
就是在原因不明時  發覺情況不對勁
to know something's wrong without knowing why.
通常是些小事情
It's always something small--
安全屋的電話有穩定的雜音
A static pop on your safe house phone,
刷卡時略微的延遲
a slight delay in authorization using your credit cards,
或是在和聯絡員談話時
or the almost imperceptible pauses
幾乎察覺不到的停頓
in conversations with your handler.
就知道情況不妙
Something's wrong,
如果你不查明是什么事
and if you don't figure out what,
你就活不過這周
you're not gonna survive the week.
現在  有人在一步步地把世界
Now someone is trying to send this world
引向戰爭
spiraling towards war,
他們想讓我做替罪羊
and they want me to take the fall,
但這兩件事他們都休想得逞
but neither of those things are gonna happen.
你得把目標的姓名告訴我
Now I need you to tell me what the name of the target is.
讓我先給我中情局的聯系人打電話
Look, let me call my CIA contact.
-她可以幫我們  -不行
- She can help us. - No.
一切跡象表明潘朵拉是由
Everything indicates that Pandora's being funded
與東歐有關聯的軍工部門資助的
by military industrial concerns linked with Eastern Europe.
他們無法完成這樣的行動
They can't pull off this operation,
必須有內應幫忙才有可能
all right, not without help from the inside.
探長  你還不懂嗎
Detective, don't you get it?
我的自己人在陷害我
My own people are setting me up.
除非我死了  不然他們不會罷手
And they're not gonna stop until I'm dead,
我是他們的調虎離山之計
because I'm the diversion.
如果每個人都在阻止我  卻沒人...
Okay, if everyone's trying to stop me, then no one--
沒人去阻止潘朵拉
Then no one's trying to stop Pandora.
除了我
No one but me.
我最后問你一次
Now I'm gonna ask you one last time,
目標是誰
Who's the target?
你好啊  托馬斯
Hello, Thomas.
這是最老的情報機關騙局了
It's the oldest intelligence con job in the book--
制造危機讓你們身處險境  他好來化險為夷
Create a crisis so you can ride in just in time to save the day.
蓋奇在耍你們
Gage was playing you.
他想讓你們覺得他是好人
He wanted you to think that he was the good guy.
他需要你們信任他
He needed your trust.
但是他為什么問我們"關鍵"是誰
Yeah, but then why did he ask us who the linchpin was?
他不是應該已經知道了嗎
Shouldn't he have known?
他在保護他的行動
He was protecting his op.
想要查明我們知情程度  然后再殺你們
He was ascertaining how much we knew before he killed you.
如果你說的對  而襲擊只是一出戲
Well, if you're right and the attack on us was staged,
那他不可能是單獨行動
then he can't be working alone.
蓋奇肯定有一個同伙
Gage must have a partner.
就是說這事還沒完
Which means it's not over.
消防人員沒控制住布萊克利公寓的火勢
Fire crews were unable to contain the blaze in Blakely's apartment.
他的研究都沒了
All of his research is gone.
在所有面部識別數據庫里搜索這個
I want you to run this through every facial rec database we have.
我要知道她是誰
I want to know who she is
而且一個十歲的女孩
and I want to know how the hell a 10-year-old girl
怎么會是引發戰爭的第一塊多米諾骨牌
could be the first domino in the march toward war.
蓋奇在哪里
Where's Gage?
在禁閉室
In the tank.
那個被你扔出窗外的人加里·哈勃
You know that guy you threw out the window-- Gary Harper?
他是我朋友
He was a friend.
那你就不該派他來找我
Then you shouldn't have sent him for me.
我們以前見過
You know, we've met before.
在柏林
In Berlin,
曼海姆那件事
the Mannheim business.
交貨的時候你也跟西班牙人在一起
You were there at the drop-off with the Spaniard.
你很棒
You were good.
你現在在為誰賣命
So who are you working for now?
那個小女孩是誰
Who's the girl?
"關鍵"是誰
Who's the linchpin?
誰讓我坐了冷板凳
Who put me in the cold?
誰陷害了我
Who set me up?
那么你認為中情局內有內應
So you think there's someone inside the CIA--
有個內鬼  叛徒
a mole, a traitor?
你是這么想得嗎
Is that what you think?
我想你或許是對的
You know, I think you could be right.
那個人就是你
And I think it's you.
你在犯下錯誤
You're making a mistake.
不  你和你的同伙在犯錯
No, you and your partner are making a mistake.
我沒有同伙
I don't have a partner.
那個殺了麥格拉和布萊克利的人
The guy out there, the one that killed McGrath and Blakely
那個把你的朋友撞進河里
and drove your friends into the water,
正在執行潘朵拉的那個人
the one carrying out operation Pandora,
他和我不是一伙人
He's not with me.
我在港口看到他了  看他的身手
I saw him at the docks, the way he moved.
他是你們的人
He's with you.
他是中情局特工
He's CIA.
你確定他在說謊嗎
Are you sure he's lying?
他沒有顯露出任何撒謊的身體特征
He's not expressing any of the physiological traits.
他接受過說謊訓練  不會露出馬腳
He's trained to lie without betraying himself.
他想挑撥我們之間的關系  讓我們互相懷疑
He wants to divide us, make us suspicious of each other.
相信我  叛徒絕對是他
Trust me. There's no mole but him.
萬一你判斷錯了  他說得是事實呢
What if you're wrong? What if he's telling the truth?
這無關緊要
That is immaterial.
現在  外面還有人
Right now, there is someone else out there,
正在準備實行潘朵拉
who is preparing to go through with Pandora,
那個小女孩是關鍵
and that girl is the key.
我們要找到她
We need to find her.
所有的數據庫都查不到
Still negative on all databases.
她是外籍人士  可能不在我們的數據庫里
She's a foreign national. She might not be in any of ours.
她的校服呢
What about her school uniform?
可以通過那個找到她嗎
Can you identify her through that?
試過了  露出的校徽太少  無法辨認
We tried. There's not enough of the crest visible to identify it.
你們真的相信嗎  謀殺一個小女孩
Do you really buy this, that killing a little girl
會導致美國的瓦解
could lead to the collapse of the United States?
太荒謬了
I mean, it just seems crazy.
布萊克利的第一個關鍵理論也很荒謬
Yeah, well, so did Blakely's first linchpin.
他們要求他制定一個非核軍事戰略
They asked him to develop a nonnuclear military strategy
能夠瓦解蘇聯
that would bring down the Soviet Union.
結果發現  我們只需開支超過他們即可
Turns out, all we had to do was outspend them.
得再審訊一下蓋奇
Need to take another run at Gage.
看來他是我們目前唯一線索了
Looks like he's all we've got.
封鎖這里
Put us on lockdown.
禁止任何人進出
No one leaves or enters the facility.
接觸燒傷  他是被近距離射殺的
Contact burns. He was shot point-blank.
怎么會沒有人聽到槍聲
How is it that nobody heard the shot?
這間房子是隔聲的
The room is soundproof.
關鍵問題在于
The real question is...
怎么會沒人看到
how come nobody saw?
有人黑了視頻流
Someone hacked the video stream.
怎么可能  你們可是中情局
How is that possible? You're the CIA.
你們的電腦是全世界最安全的
You have the most secure computers in the world.
蓋奇有可能沒說謊
It's possible because Gage was right.
局里有叛徒
There's a mole in the CIA,
那個人就是這個團隊中的一員
and he's in this unit.
封鎖完畢
Facility's locked down.
所有人員都在崗
All personnel have been accounted for.
有多少人有權限進入那個房間
How many people had access to that room?
18個
18.
長官  我已經隔離了篡改視頻的子程序
Ma'am, I've isolated the subroutine used to doctor the video.
它嵌在一個蠕蟲病毒里才沒被發現
It was embedded in a software worm to escape detection.
就是說查不出它的來源
Then there's no way to tell where it came from.
我或許可以使用還原算法
I may be able to use a reductive logarithm
以分離出它進入系統的路徑
to isolate the pathway it took through the system.
這樣也許就能知道來源了
It might tell us where it was loaded.
-你能做到嗎  -我試試
- You can do that? - I can try.
開始吧
Do it.
我完全不懂他們在說什么
Wow. I got no idea what they're talking about,
可這好令人好激動啊
But this is very exciting.
好了  開始追蹤
There it is. Starting the trace.
找到了
Got it.
這就是上傳病毒的終端地址
That's the terminal address where the virus was uploaded.
是誰的
Whose is it?
杜蘭特工
Agent Trahn's.
什么  不是我
What? No.
-你們弄錯了  -把手放在顯眼位置
- There's been a mistake. - Get your hands where I can see them.
趴在地上  現在  快點  趴下
Get down on the ground now! Do it now! Down now!
等一下  那是個誘餌
Wait! It's a decoy.
黑客盜用了那個IP  不是杜蘭
The hacker piggybacked the I.P. It's not trahn.
那到底是誰
Then who is it?
上傳病毒的那人用了杜蘭的終端IP
Whoever uploaded it used Trahn's terminal I.P.
隱藏了自己的身份
to hide their I.D.
他很強  但我更勝一籌
They're good, but I'm better.
我提取出了用戶的帳號密碼
I've isolated the user's pass code.
我正在解碼
I'm de-encrypting now.
IP地址識別
開始進行人員比對
Run a personnel match.
馬丁 丹博格
馬丁
Martin?
不是我  索菲
No, Soph.
我是忠誠的  你是知道的
I'm loyal. You know I'm loyal.
那把槍放下
Then put the gun down.
把槍放下
Put it down!
好的
Okay.
好吧
All right. Okay.
馬丁  只要你開槍她就死  所有人后退
Martin! No! You shoot, she dies. Everyone, back up now.
-馬丁  別這樣  -大家后退
- Martin, don't. Don't do it. - Back up now! Back--back up now!
按那個
Hit it.
馬丁  停下
Martin, don't.
馬丁  別這樣  馬丁
Martin, don't! Martin.
馬丁  把槍放下
Put the gun down, martin.
謝了  但我更想保命
Thanks, but I'd rather live.
把電梯停下
Shut the elevator down.
連上了
I'm in.
各就各位  我把電梯降回來
Standby. I'm bringing it back down.
你是不可能發現的
There's no way you could've known.
不可能嗎  當我們剛得知"潘朵拉"
No? When we first got wind of Pandora,
丹博格是首先找到所有關聯的人
Danberg was the one who found all the connections.
是他追蹤到蓋奇的
He was the one who traced it to Gage,
只為不讓我們過于接近他
all so we wouldn't get too close to him.
他甚至勸我踢走你們二位
He even tried to convince me to get rid of you two.
最糟糕的是
And worst of all,
他可能不是單獨行動
he may not be working alone.
潘朵拉的影響很大
The implications of Pandora are huge.
我不懂為什么我們自己人會
I don't understand how one of our own would actually
希望把我們國家甚至世界攪入戰爭
want to plunge the country or the world into war.
金錢  理想  都說不通
Money, ideology-- none of it makes any sense.
動機不重要
Well, the motives don't matter.
重要的是阻止潘朵拉
All that matters is stopping Pandora.
蓋奇說他聽到些風聲
Gage said he picked up chatter.
他說行動明天執行
He said it's going down tomorrow.
跟我們聽到的一致
We've heard the same thing,
就是說我們的時間所剩無幾
which means, we don't have any time.
必須要找到小女孩
We have to find her.
我們一定遺漏了什么
Well, there's gotta be something that we missed,
某些能夠幫助我們找到她的細節
some detail that'll help us figure out who she is.
我們已經在所有數據庫里搜索了
We've run it through every database we have.
我們查了能查的一切
We have looked through everything.
不是一切
Not everything.
你們監控全球地形  對吧
You guys maintain a topographical survey of the earth, right?
是的  怎么
Yeah. Why?
不要搜索女孩
So don't search for the girl.
搜索這些山脈
Run the mountains.
如果知道她來自哪兒  就可以縮小搜索范圍了
If we know where she's from, we can narrow down our search.
你真天才
You are a genius.
這要花多長時間
How long will this take?
地球很大
It's a big world.
我們調出了所有的位于
We've pulled anything arid
北緯60度到南緯60度之間的干旱地帶
and everything above and below 60 degrees latitude,
但他們還在估算  也許要32個小時
But they're estimating, it could take 32 hours.
會是個漫漫長夜啊
Sounds like a long night.
我去倒些咖啡
I'll get some coffees.
他總是很體貼
He was always thoughtful.
你喜歡他
You like him.
是的  曾經
I did. Once.
你們之間發生了什么
S-so what happened?
如果你不介意的話
If you don't mind my asking.
是這樣的
Well, um,
你有過
Well, you ever...
認識一個人  然后有了一種...
meet someone and--and have that...
強烈的吸引力的經歷嗎
intense attraction right away...
那種張力
You know, that tension?
我們抗拒了幾個月  后來
Well, we fought it for months, and then...
后來我們再也不能忍受了
And then we just couldn't stand it anymore.
但之后  感覺
But afterward, it--it was like
那種張力是我們
that tension was all we...
僅有的
had really in.
除此之外  我們之間剩下的只有
And without it, all we were left with was that...
把彼此逼瘋的那些瑣事
Well, those things that drove us crazy about each other.
你知道他那個人
I mean, you know how he can be.
對
Yeah.
我知道
Yeah, I do.
有時我真希望我沒跟他上床
Sometimes I wish we had never slept together...
應該一直那樣曖昧著
Had kept that longing.
連咖啡杯上都印著"中情局"  太酷了
Even your coffee mugs say "CIA." That is so cool.
如果我們能成功拯救世界
Well, we save the world,
也許我會給你一個
maybe I'll let you keep one.
有動力了
Incentive.
照片里的地貌與
Uh, the topography matches terrain
中國浙江省的地理形勢吻合
in the Chinese province of Zhejiang,
就在杭州城外
just outside the city of Hangzhou.
靠近上海
That's near Shanghai.
找出區域內所有學校的校服徽章
Pull up all school uniform insignias from that region.
等等  右上角那
Wait. Right there on the top right corner.
它們顏色相同
They're the same color.
上海第12女子中學
Shanghai No.12 Girls' School.
學校有網址嗎
Do they have a web site?
有  但有密碼保護  開始解鎖
It's password protected. Picking the lock now.
黑進學校的照片檔案  進行面部識別
Hack into their photo archives and run facial rec.
連帶注解進行對照
Bring up the captions and compare.
掃描照片
97%吻合
找到了  米婭·岡宏
Got her. Mia Ganghong.
有關于她的資料嗎
What do we know about her?
不是很多
Uh, not much.
僅知道她是祥和碧玉·岡宏的女兒
Just that she's the daughter of Xiang and Biyu Ganghong.
祥·岡宏
Xiang Ganghong?
誰是祥·岡宏
Who's Xiang Ganghong?
一個中國商人
He's a Chinese businessman.
同財政部長和
With close ties to the Finance Minister
執政黨關系密切
and members of the ruling party.
為何他女兒會成為目標
Well, why is his daughter targeted?
祥是有權支配要職任命
Xiang is a kingmaker.
他對政府經濟政策的制定
He's extremely influential
有充分的影響力
in shaping his government's economic policy.
他通過出售中國軍事硬件致富
He made his fortune selling Chinese military hardware.
有時會賣給我們的敵人
Sometimes to our enemies.
但基于他支持中國購買美國國債的原因
But we left him alone because he was supportive
我們聽之任之
of China's purchase of U.S. Debt.
現在如果有人想除掉祥
Now if someone were to take out Xiang,
對我們也沒多大影響
not that much would change.
但如果他的女兒在一場拙劣的
But if his daughter were killed
暗殺中被殺的話
in a botched assassination attempt,
中國會追查到
and the Chinese were able to trace it
美國政府
back to the U.S. Government?
進而追查到蓋奇
The trail that led to Gage.
不難想象祥會利用
It's conceivable that Xiang could use
其充分的影響力
his considerable influence
只手讓中國停止購買美國國債
to single handedly end China's purchase of the U.S. Debt.
國家繼續赤字開支
This country runs on deficit spending.
如果國家借不到錢
If--if we can't borrow money--
就不能履行國家義務
We couldn't meet our obligations,
政府就會倒閉
the government would shut down.
財政緊縮會被強制執行
Austerity measures would be imposed.
我們將喪失在全球部署軍事的能力
We'd lose our ability to deploy our military around the world.
隨之美國宣布中立
And then with the U.S. neutralized,
我們的敵人就會
our enemies would be able
瘋狂掠奪獲取利益
to explore their interests unchecked.
就是這樣
That's right.
還會爆發地區沖突
And there would be an explosion of regional conflicts,
其中的任何一個都能引發全球戰爭
any one of which could send us toward global war.
一場我們甚至沒能力打贏的戰爭
A war that we might not even be able to win.
一塊多米諾骨牌被撞倒  整個世界將會翻天覆地
One domino knocked down, the entire world changes.
我們找到祥了
We've located Xiang.
一小時前他和中國代表團
He and a chinese delegation
剛剛抵達肯尼迪國際機場
just landed at J.F.K. an hour ago.
他來紐約了
He's here?
參加麥金利大廈舉行的聯合國貿易會議
For a U.N. Trade Conference at the Mckinley Building.
他們在過來的路上
They're on their way there now.
長官  他女兒跟他在一起
And, ma'am, his daughter's with him.
如果現在召集
If we call it in,
我能找到安保小分隊待命
I can get a protective detail waiting.
你覺得警察能夠阻攔
You think your cops are gonna be able to stop
中情局訓練有素的特工嗎
CIA-trained operatives?
他們會送命的
They'd just end up dead.
另外  如泄露半點風聲
Besides, if word of this gets out,
將會引發空前絕后的國際爭端
it could spark an international incident of epic proportions.
我們得收拾殘局  而不是制造事端
We need to clean up the mess, not make one.
就我們嗎
We and what army?
你說過我們不能相信別人
You said we couldn't trust the others
因為他們可能同丹博格是一伙的
because they could be working with Danberg.
此處不是中情局在紐約的唯一駐點
This is not the only CIA Station in New York.
我已經叫另外一隊人趕去現場
I've got another field team on its way.
封鎖這里  等我消息
You seal it up until you hear from me.
禁止電話進出
No calls going in or out.
我不能冒險
I'm not taking any chances.
遵命  長官
Yes, ma'am.
科里根特工  這是貝克特探長和卡塞爾先生
Agent Corrigan, Detective Beckett and Mr. Castle.
代表團人呢
Where's the delegation?
五分鐘路程
Five minutes away.
我們的人就位了嗎
We in position?
走廊上部署了人  街對面也有人監視
We have teams in the lobby and spotters across the street.
丹博格呢
What about Danberg?
一名守衛認出他45分鐘前
A guard I.D.'ed him as having entered the building
進入大廈
45 minutes ago.
已有專人就位  得到授權"見即殺"
We have crews in place authorized to take him out,
但還沒找到他拍檔
but we still haven't identified his partner.
無論發生何事  確保小女孩的安全
Whatever happens, keep the girl alive.
明白嗎
Do you understand me?
是的  長官
Yes, ma'am.
我們要去哪
Where are we going?
這邊
This way.
咱們跑這來干嗎
What are we doing down here?
咱們不是應該去大堂嗎
Shouldn't we be headed for the lobby?
卡塞爾
Castle.
抱歉
Sorry.
你這是干嗎
What are you doing?
丹博格根本就不是叛徒  對吧
Danberg wasn't the mole, was he?
你才是
You are.
去殺了那個女孩  這兩個人交給我
Go kill the girl. I'll take care of these two.
一直都是你嗎
It was you this whole time?
恐怕是的
I'm afraid so.
那你又何必把我們帶來這里呢
Then why bring us here?
何不直接把我們留在那邊
Why not just leave us at the facility?
因為你從不肯善罷甘休
Because you just don't stop.
你非得了解整件事不可
You need to know the story, the whole story.
如果有些細節對不上  你就窮追不舍
And if something doesn't add up, you just don't let go.
你以為我帶你們來干什么
Why do you think I brought you inside?
我是在保護這次行動
I was protecting the op.
就像你為了保護行動
Like you were trying to protect the operation
殺了布萊克利和麥格拉
when you killed Blakely and McGrath?
你陷害了蓋奇
You set up Gage.
要使我們的計劃成功
Well, for the linchpin to work,
必須讓中國人怪罪美國政府
the Chinese have to blame the U.S. government.
整個行動必須讓人追蹤到中情局頭上來
The operation has to trace back to the CIA.
當你需要防止自己暴露時  你就把他給殺了
And when you needed to cover your tracks, you killed him.
所以現在需要其他替罪羊
So then you needed someone else.
你需要丹博格
You needed Danberg.
索菲亞
Sophia...
第三次世界大戰  為什么
World War III, why?
這么說吧  這世界上有些黨派
Let's just say, there are certain parties
會不惜一切代價來重組這個世界
who will pay anything to reshape the world.
我不信
I don't buy it.
我認識的那個索菲亞決不會為了錢
The Sophia I know wouldn't sell out her country,
或是其它任何原因當叛國賊
not for money, not for anything.
那就你就錯了  里奇
Well, that's one thing you got wrong, Rick.
這根本就不是我的國家
給我跪下
On your knees right now.
你們倆都跪下
Both of you.
你不可能從這件事中全身而退
You're never gonna get away with this.
我當然可以
Of course I will.
我就告訴他們我們盡了全力  卻還是晚了一步
I'll just tell them how we all tried to stop it and couldn't,
而你們倆則在我們執行任務的過程中遇害了
and the two of you were killed in the process,
兇手當然就是丹博格
by Danberg, of course.
別擔心  我會把你倆塑造成英雄的
Don't worry. I'll make it sound heroic.
你父親會為你感到自豪的
Your father will be very proud.
我父親
My father?
拜托  你不會以為你當初能來中情局
Well, you don't think you gained special access
是因為你的魅力吧
to the CIA back then because of your charm.
你還真是不知情啊
You really don't know, do you?
看來你永遠都不會知道了
I guess you never will.
不
No!
快走
Come on.
只有咱們三個  時間不多了
It's just us, and we're out of time.
你沒事吧
Are you okay?
他沒事
He's fine.
他沒事  他沒事
He's good. He's okay.
先生  你沒事吧  你沒事吧
Sir, are you all right? You all right?
-這邊  -沒錯  也許咱們該出去透透氣
- This way.  - Yeah, maybe we should go outside.
你覺得這一切到底是怎么回事
So what do you think this was all about?
他們沒告訴你嗎
They didn't tell you?
什么
What? Th --
他們告訴你了
They -- they told you?
她反咬我一口
Once she turned me out,
我也就很快明白了事情的真相
it didn't take long to put the pieces together.
但是我當時只能旁觀
But all I could do was watch
等著她下一步行動
and wait for her to make her move.
很難相信她居然是個叛徒
Hard to believe she was a traitor.
一切都是裝出來的
It was all an act.
蘭利[中情局總部]認為她有可能是前克格勃成員
Langley thinks she may have been a former K.G.B. sleeper
隨著蘇維埃的解散  她也就開始了漂泊
set adrift when the Soviet Union broke up.
她留在局里是因為她無處可去
Stayed with the company because she had nowhere else to go.
直到更好的機會出現
Till a better offer came along.
你們查出來她替誰工作
Did you ever find out who she was working for,
誰才是潘朵拉的幕后黑手了嗎
who was behind Pandora?
沒有  就算我查出來了也不能告訴你
No, and even if I did, I couldn't tell you.
丹博格探員
Agent Danberg...
索菲亞跟我說了一些事情
Sophia said something,
她說我父親在中情局工作
Something about my father being in the CIA.
你對此會不會也有所耳聞呢
Would you know anything about that?
我恐怕不知道
I'm afraid I don't.
抱歉
Sorry.
貝克特探長
Oh, uh, Detective Beckett.
給你
Here.
我讓我的人處理了一下你的車
I had our guys, uh, take care of your car.
你把我的車從河里撈出來了
You pulled my car out of the river?
是啊  你會發現車比新的還贊
Yep. I think you will find it better than new.
謝謝
Thank you.
這是我們該做的
It's the least that we could do.
保重
Take care.
你覺得她說的關于我父親的事
You think she was telling the truth
是真話嗎
about my father?
如果是的話倒是可以解釋
I mean, that would explain
他為什么突然間就人間蒸發了
why he completely disappeared.
我
I...
我認為索菲亞說了很多謊話
I think that Sophia told a lot of lies.
你肯定覺得不好受吧
Must be tough,
發現她是個叛國賊
finding out that she's a traitor,
尤其是你以她為原型創作了克萊拉·斯瑞克
especially after you based Clara Strike on her and all.
怎么說呢
Hmm. Well...
克萊拉最開始是以索菲亞為原型  但
Clara started off as Sophia, but...
她后來變得更像你
she ended up being more like you, you know --
聰明  勇猛  善良
smart, fierce, kind.
這也是我被你吸引的原因
I think that's one of the reasons I was drawn to you
像繆斯一樣吸引
as a muse.
你覺得布萊克利博士
You think Dr. Blakely was right...
對關鍵理論的判斷是對的嗎
about the linchpin?
你覺得咱們真的拯救了世界嗎
Do you think we actually saved the world?
我認為我們救了一個小女孩的命
I think that we saved a little girl's life,
這對我來說就足夠了
and that's enough for me.